<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nyheters on Imint</title>
    <link>http://imint.se/nyheter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nyheters on Imint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>sv-se</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://imint.se/nyheter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Imint i Swedish Startup Space</title>
      <link>http://imint.se/nyheter/20150709-swedish-startup-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://imint.se/nyheter/20150709-swedish-startup-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Swedish Startup Space skrev en positiv &lt;a href=&#34;http://swedishstartupspace.com/2015/07/09/imint-uppsala-auto-zoom/&#34;&gt;artikel&lt;/a&gt; om Imint.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Vidhance Could Soon Replace Live Video Producers&#34; - TechCrunch Covers New Roadmap</title>
      <link>http://imint.se/nyheter/20150202-vidhance-could-soon-replace-Live-video-producers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 16:02:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://imint.se/nyheter/20150202-vidhance-could-soon-replace-Live-video-producers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an article published on June 22nd, 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com&#34;&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt; editor &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/author/frederic-lardinois/&#34;&gt;Frederic Lardinois&lt;/a&gt; digs into the new Vidhance® Mobile roadmap, and make insightful predictions on how this technology could change the media landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the full article &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2015/06/22/imints-Vidhance-algorithms-could-soon-replace-live-video-producers/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coming functionality of Vidhance Mobile was also covered on &lt;a href=&#34;http://swedishstartupspace.com/2015/07/09/imint-uppsala-auto-zoom/&#34;&gt;Swedish Startup Space&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imint Showcase New Vidhance Mobile Capability - Live Autozoom Enables Consumers to Capture Powerful Videos</title>
      <link>http://imint.se/nyheter/20150202-imint-showcase-new-vidhance-mobile-capability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 12:37:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://imint.se/nyheter/20150202-imint-showcase-new-vidhance-mobile-capability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The video software company Imint has revealed new disruptive functionality in its Vidhance® Mobile software platform. The real-time software, running on a portable camera device such as a smartphone, enables user to automatically capture smooth and stable cut-outs, following objects of interest with cinematic pans and zooms. The Autozoom capability is a result of earlier works by Imint within the defense segment, and the company has fused robust algorithms for object detection, tracking and sizing, and added videographic rules for zoom and composition, to give consumers instant and effortless videos that are far more interesting and engaging from more traditional “shaky surveillance camera”-clips. Regardless of the filming situation – your friend’s adventurous cliff dive, your daughter’s soccer game, or your grandfather driving away on his new HD motorbike – Autozoom solves a problem recognized by most. Either the filmmaker keeps a wide angle throughout the clip, resulting in a boring, disconnected viewing experience, or tries to fiddle with manual zoom, with terrible result with magnified shakes and the object more often out of the frame then in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;boxedimg &#34;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;http://imint.se/newspost/Imint-Showcase-New-Vidhance-Mobile-Capability/ropeway_snapshot.png&#34;/&gt;
	
		&lt;figcaption&gt;Original video to the left, and with Vidhance Mobile Live Autozoom to the right. The functionality change the whole video experience, and creates dynamic clips that engage the viewer.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imint is a software company based in Uppsala, Sweden, with its background in academic research in image analysis and video optimizations. Imint&amp;rsquo;s efficient real-time Vidhance algorithms has been field deployed for several years in demanding defense- and industrial applications. In October 2014, Imint publically launched its first prototype of Vidhance Mobile, with its software re-targeted for smartphones. Vidhance Mobile is an intelligent software platform that can added to the phone&amp;rsquo;s operating system or directly into apps, giving the smartphone or app respectively, a clear edge in camera capabilities and giving all users a smooth video experience. The first feature introduced in Vidhance Mobile was true cinematic video stabilization. Following this launch, Imint has been relentless in its R&amp;amp;D efforts, pushing the envelope further, to bring consumers new disruptive ways to capture breathtaking videos, for sharing or live streaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;boxedimg &#34;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;http://imint.se/newspost/Imint-Showcase-New-Vidhance-Mobile-Capability/uxstart.png&#34;/&gt;
	
		&lt;figcaption&gt;Example of Ux; using also the motion-in-motion detector in Vidhance, the user can automatically be presented with suggestions on interesting objects, end quickly enable Live Autozoom.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The revealed Autzoom feature addition to Vidhance Mobile, works by combining several layers of real-time video analysis and optimizations. Imint’s technology for object tracking and sizing has been deployed in demanding applications such as military drone surveillance and air traffic management, and is very robust in terms of object size, shape, color, orientation and illumination. When enabled, the software automatically moves closer to the object of interest, and compose a more engaging close-up experience. Several ways for user interaction is available, from simpler user guidance by tapping on the preview screen where the object of interest is, to use the automatic moving object detection also a part of legacy Vidhance applications within defense applications, such as airborne maritime surveillance. When enabled, the user can be presented with simple overlays to the preview, with object recommendations, and while autozoom is running, an icon for disengaging and searching for new objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon Mika, CTO of Imint, gave further description of the new functionality, and next steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are very happy with the first results – we had a hunch this would be extremely helpful for effortless creation of stunning video clips, but when the first results were out of the labs we all knew this was a killer feature. As a positive side note, it also offers realistic alternatives to how to utilize high resolution sensors. Not all situations calls for recording in 4K, as video files get huge, and it might not be convenient for quick sharing of clips on social media. With Vidhance Mobile Autozoom, the user automatically get scaled down version – but covering the interesting parts in a way that looks more professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;boxedimg &#34;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;http://imint.se/newspost/Imint-Showcase-New-Vidhance-Mobile-Capability/composing.png&#34;/&gt;
	
		&lt;figcaption&gt;Vidhance Mobile Live Autozoom is being further improved, to increase automatic optimal frame composition, using motion patterns (such as direction) and object recognition.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re now extending this functionality with additional intelligence, such as using motion patterns and object recognition for optimal frame composition. We believe that for consumer video to become ubiquitous, on-the-go recording should just work, and users should be surprised on how good videographers they have become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andreas Lifvendahl, Imint’s CEO, added to Mika’s comments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am truly impressed by the team’s ability to spin out innovations in a short time – we’re revealing Autozoom only nine months after the first Android-based version of Vidhance Mobile was first showcased. The timing is also excellent, as we see a second wave of interest around mobile video, driven by live social media applications like Meerkat and Periscope. After an initial hype, we believe user expectations on higher quality streams will need to be addressed to keep engagement to this medium. With Vidhance Mobile, we have followed a gap analysis approach; what are consumers with smartphones main shortcomings compared to a professional film crew? Our video stabilization and adaptive regional contrast optimization solved the basic problems on video quality. Autozoom enables users to emulate professional gear on tripods, doing stable close-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asked about next steps in this gap-closing approach, Lifvendahl concluded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously the main remaining tasks is to use several cameras, and do a professional production mix of different angles, positions and distances, as broadcast companies has taught us it should look. Well, there are no shortage of smartphones around, so the interesting problems is how to connect these, how an automatic “cloud producer” would do the mixing, and what kind of metadata that needs to flow between ad-hoc contributors and such cloud producer. We will reveal more on our roadmap here at a later stage; we are currently filing a number of patents, as we believe we have solved some of the messier technology hurdles here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short examples of Live Autozoom can be seen on Youtube:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-container&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/qIletnpr8xk&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-container&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/BA3UTWaXWds&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-container&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/8WocPfvrp2I&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imint&#39;s CEO Interviewed by Breakit (in Swedish)</title>
      <link>http://imint.se/nyheter/20150608-ceo-interviewd-by-breakit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://imint.se/nyheter/20150608-ceo-interviewd-by-breakit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://breakit.se&#34;&gt;Breakit&lt;/a&gt; - the new Swedish news site on technology and startups - interviews Imint CEO Andreas Lifvendahl.See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://redeye.solidtango.com/widgets/embed/epsjxsbb?auto_play=false&#34;&gt;full video interview&lt;/a&gt; (in Swedish).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imint Keeps Growing - We Welcome Bettina, David and Ziquan</title>
      <link>http://imint.se/nyheter/20150326-we-welcome-bettina-david-and-ziquan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 13:10:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://imint.se/nyheter/20150326-we-welcome-bettina-david-and-ziquan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imint has brought in more talents to its engineering team; and we welcome Bettina Selig, David Piuva Forsgren and Ziquan Yu, who all recently joined Imint. They all add valuable expertise and knowledge to the accelerating research, development and product building efforts. This is supportive of the goal of taking Imint to a leading position within mobile video and user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bettina Selig has PhD in Computerized Image Analysis from the Center for Image Analysis, Uppsala. As part of her PhD research, Bettina was also a visiting student at TU Delft and Rotterdam Ophthalmic Institute, the Netherlands. Bettina also holds a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science from Freie Universität Berlin. Bettina&amp;rsquo;s primary research expertise is within automatic image segmentation algorithms, but her experience within robotic vision will also give valuable contributions to Imint. In this field, during her master studies at Freie Universität, Bettina was strongly involved in building up the vision system for autonomous robots playing soccer. Her team FU-Fighters was the proud winner of the RoboCup World Championship in Osaka in 2005. During her time at Center for Image Analysis, she also taught and mentored bachelor and master students at Uppsala University in the field of image analysis, pattern recognition and robotics, including a full term project on rescue robots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Forsgren Piuva has a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science from Uppsala University. David has been devoted to computer games and graphics for almost two decades, and has developed both his own graphics&amp;rsquo;s engine and programming language. David received the best in class award from Lundellska skolan gymnasium, and was nominated to Swedish Game Awards for best execution in 2008. With this background, and his strong interest in both audio- and imaging algorithms, he has already contributed substantially to Imint&amp;rsquo;s development on contrast optimization technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;boxedimg &#34;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&#34;http://imint.se/newspost/We-welcome-Bettina-David-and-Ziquan/bettina_dominic_david_final.jpg&#34;/&gt;
	
		&lt;figcaption&gt;Ziquan Yu, Bettina Selig and David Forsgren Piuva&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ziquan &amp;ldquo;Dominic&amp;rdquo; Yu holds a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Electronic and Information Engineering from Northwestern Polytechnical University, Xi&amp;rsquo;an, China, a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Electrical Engineering from Dalarna University, Sweden, and a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computational Science from Uppsala University. Ziquan&amp;rsquo;s experience in object identification and tracking methods and algorithms, honed in his as research assistant at the Center for Image Analysis, is adding to Imint&amp;rsquo;s further tuning of its core video motion algorithms. During his work as research assistant, Ziquan developed algorithms to identify and track individual bees in a beehive, in a project under the Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences. Outside his academic work, he has devoted his time to computer vision projects, including novel ways to use the Kinect technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon Mika, CTO at Imint, are proud of these additions to the team, and commented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &amp;lsquo;triplet&amp;rsquo; of very clever engineers makes a superb combination of solid analytical skills, experience in using a researcher&amp;rsquo;s toolbox, personal devotion to the subject matter, and a can-do pragmatic way of achieving results. This enables us to put in the turbo drive in rolling out tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s technology enablers for mobile video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic Yu is happy to be on board with Imint, and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking image analysis methods into practical use in products is the key drive for my motivation. I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have the opportunity to join the Imint team - it is a smart and supportive group of people, set to accomplish something of significance for mobile video, and I am pleased to be able to contribute with my unique skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to these recent hires, Imint has also two bright master thesis students onboard, as part of the co-operation with the Center for Image Analysis. More information on these projects will be made official as the projects successfully wraps up. Part of the work is centered on novel algorithmic research in mapping mobile video to user experience, and core algorithm adaptation for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imint Listed as &#34;Company to Watch&#34; by Leading Business Journal</title>
      <link>http://imint.se/nyheter/20150219-imint-a-company-to-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 13:23:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://imint.se/nyheter/20150219-imint-a-company-to-watch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imint was listed as a &amp;ldquo;Must watch&amp;rdquo; company by the Swedish weekly business journal &lt;a href=&#34;http://va.se&#34;&gt;Veckans Affärer&lt;/a&gt;, in a theme article looking at drone-related companies. The article is a part of a start-up watch in co-operation with &lt;a href=&#34;http://almi.se/almi-invest/about-almi-invest&#34;&gt;Almi Invest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article can be read &lt;a href=&#34;http://va.se/nyheter/2015/02/19/smarta-dronare&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (in Swedish).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imint is Expanding - New Job Openings</title>
      <link>http://imint.se/nyheter/20150202-imint-is-expanding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 13:33:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://imint.se/nyheter/20150202-imint-is-expanding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imint is in rapid expansion, and has opened up a number of interesting position within the field of image research, product management, software development and technical marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imint encourage interested candidates to check out our &lt;a href=&#34;http://imint.se/career&#34;&gt;job postings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>